https://www.promod.eu/help/general-sales-conditions/categorie/05#righttocancel

Purpose
These terms govern the sale of the products presented on this site by the company:
Promod SAS
Chemin du verseau
59700 Marcq en Baroeul
France
Phone number: +33 (0) 3 20 01 10 00 / Fax number: +33 (0) 3 20 01 10 01
Email address: service@promod.eu
Registered in France in the Lille Metropole Register of Commerce and Companies
(R.C.S. LILLE METROPOLE), under No. 685 420 606
VAT No. FR 55 685 420 606
Publisher of www.promod.eu (Publisher manager: Frédéric Lefebvre, Hosting by: Coreye)
Hereinafter “Promod”
And
Everyone who visits or buys on www.promod.eu
Hereinafter "Net Surfer"
These terms and conditions apply to the use of this website and by proceeding further and/or placing an order you agree to be bound by them. If you do not agree to be bound by them, you should leave this website now.
The terms and conditions apply to the purchase of products offered for sale through this website. We may change these conditions from time to time without notice to you. Changes will apply to any subsequent orders received. It is your responsibility to check regularly to see if any changes have been made to these conditions. We reserve the right to modify or withdraw this website at any time without liability to you.
Each contract shall be governed by these conditions which contain the entire agreement between you and us in respect of its subject matter and supersedes any previous agreements relating to such matter.
We store the contract’s content and will send you the details of your order via email. The general terms can be found here at all times. The details about your recent orders can be found via your customer login.
As an internet shopper you must:
Not order products via this website if you are not resident in the European Union and aged 16 years or over,
Not resell Promod products just after purchasing them.
Top
Definitions
"Conditions" means these terms and conditions;
"Contract" means the contract incorporating these conditions which comes into force when you place an order and we confirm acceptance of such order by means of an email to you;
"Order" means an order placed by you via this website for one or more products;
"Personal information" means all and any information provided by you in an order or when registering on this website to include and not limited to your name, address and card details;
"Product" means any product advertised on this website;
"EU" means the European Union;
"We/Us" means Promod SAS - Chemin du verseau - 59700 Marcq en Baroeul, France, registered in France in the Lille Metropole Register of Commerce and Companies
(R.C.S. LILLE METROPOLE), under No. 685 420 606, VAT No. FR 55 685 420 606
"Website" means www.promod.eu;
"You" means a user of this website.
Top
Article 1: Products
All goods are subject to availability and the details given are as accurate and complete as possible.
Limited stocks available.
We take all reasonable measures to ensure that details, measurements and descriptions of products given on this website are as accurate and complete as possible. But there may be variations between these and the products themselves.
Top
Article 2: Prices
All prices appearing on this website are inclusive of VAT (where applicable) at the current rates.
The cost of your order will be the price of the products ordered plus the appropriate delivery charge.
Please see "Delivery information" for more information on delivery rates.
All goods are subject to availability and the details given are as accurate and complete as possible.
Due to circumstances beyond our control, prices may have to be altered, including any variations in the rate of VAT.
We shall be entitled by notifying you to cancel any contract, in whole or in part, to the extent that for the purchase of a product the price was, in error, stated incorrectly on the website. The cancellation should be limited solely to this product.
Top
Article 3: Order and cancellation of order
You recognize to accept these Terms and Conditions by placing an order.
You must not order products via this website if you are not resident in the European Union and not aged 16 years or over. All orders are subject to acceptance by us. All products are subject to availability.
To enable you to change your mind until the last step of the order, Promod has created confirmation and acceptation screens to confirm the order. As soon as you have clicked on the button “Order & Pay”, the order is considered definitive. An order confirmation is then sent by email to you. This email confirms order acceptation but does not guarantee that the product is available in stock.
RIGHT TO CANCEL
You have the right to cancel this contract within 14 days without giving any reason.
The cancellation period will expire after 14 days from the day, on which you acquire, or a third party other than the carrier and indicated by you acquires, physical possession of the goods.
To exercise the right to cancel, you must inform us
Promod SAS – Customer Service
Chemin du verseau
59700 Marcq en Baroeul
France
Phone number: +33 (0) 3 20 01 10 00
Fax number: +33 (0) 3 20 01 10 01
Email address: service@promod.eu
of your decision to cancel this contract by a clear statement (e.g. a letter sent by post, fax or e-mail).
You may use the model cancellation form available in your account and attached to every delivery confirmation email, but it is not obligatory.
To meet the cancellation deadline, it is sufficient for you to send your communication concerning your exercise of the right to cancel before the cancellation period has expired.
Effects of cancellation:
If you cancel this contract, we will reimburse to you all payments received from you, including the costs of delivery (except for the supplementary costs arising if you chose a type of delivery other than the least expensive type of standard delivery offered by us).
We may make a deduction from the reimbursement for loss in value of any goods supplied, if the loss is the result of unnecessary handling by you.
We will make the reimbursement without undue delay, and not later than –
(a) 14 days after the day we receive back from you any goods supplied, or
(b) (if earlier) 14 days after the day you provide evidence that you have returned the goods.
We will make the reimbursement using the same means of payment as you used for the initial transaction, unless you have expressly agreed otherwise; in any event, you will not incur any fees as a result of the reimbursement.
We may withhold reimbursement until we have received the goods back or you have supplied evidence of having sent back the goods, whichever is the earliest.
You shall send back the goods or hand them over to us, without undue delay and in any event not later than 14 days from the day on which you communicate your cancellation from this contract to us. The deadline is met if you send back the goods before the period of 14 days has expired.
Please see "Returns and exchanges" for more information on how to return the parcel.
You will have to bear the direct cost of returning the goods.
You are only liable for any diminished value of the goods resulting from the handling other than what is necessary to establish the nature, characteristics and functioning of the goods.
Top
Article 4: Payment
You can pay online via credit card.
We accept payment via Visa, Mastercard and Carte Bleue.
In the interests of secure payment, the Promod website uses the Sogenactif online payment service. This service incorporates the SSL security standard. The confidential data (16 digit credit card number, expiry date) is encrypted (encoded) and transmitted to the Sogenactif server but is not transmitted to our server.
When you confirm your order:
Your payment application is routed real-time Sogenactif’s secure electronic payment management system.
This sends an authorisation request to the credit card network.
The electronic payment manager delivers an electronic certificate.
The occurrence of non-payment due to the fraudulent use of a credit card will lead to the registration of the details associated with your order in a data file created. An incorrect statement or anomaly could also lead to individual processing procedures.
The account is not debited with the amount until the goods ordered have been dispatched.
If your items are no longer in stock, the amount of the cancelled articles will be duly deducted from the total debited amount and your account will be re-credited with the appropriate amount within 3 working days after our debit of the total amount that included the cancelled articles.
For gift orders, the invoice will be sent directly to the purchaser’s email address. The delivery note and the return form that will be inserted into the parcel, does not include any prices and payment details.
Top
Article 5: Credit card anti-fraud actions
The data gathered by Promod on the website is intended for Promod. You can give or refuse your consent to the data gathered via this order being used in connection with the Promod customer files and likewise to it being used by third parties.
In accordance with the law No. 78-17 of the 6 01 1978 (informatique et libertés), you have a right at all times to access and amend personal information. This right of correction can be exercised online, or you can direct a request by email to the following address: service@promod.eu
When you place an order for the first time, you are allocated a password that you can change. The password you choose should contain at least 6 characters. You will be able to use it for every new order without having to enter all your details, apart from your credit card details which must be entered every time you order. It will also enable you to check any orders you have ongoing.
If you like, you can opt to be informed by email of any special deals on the website. This option can be chosen online.
You can ask to be removed from the customer files. This choice can be exercised online and will take effect once you no longer have any orders going through.
Finally, if you don't wish to receive offers from other companies and organisations, just send an e-mail to the following address: service@promod.eu, indicating your surname, first name, address, e-mail, telephone and confidential code.
Conforming to the data protection act of 6th January 1978, you have the right to access, modify or challenge your personal data information by writing, with proof of your identity, to service@promod.eu.
Promod reserves the right to check personal information provided by a customer and to take necessary follow-up action (such as asking for further proof or cancelling the order) to be sure that the person whose bank account is debited is indeed the same person who requested the order and also to avoid any fraudulent use whatsoever of credit card information.
Top
Article 6: Security on the website
In order to offer secure payment, the Promod.eu site uses the secure payment services of Sogenactif. This service conforms to SSL secure online payment norms. Confidential information (the 16-figure credit card number, expiration date and card verification code) are transmitted in encrypted form on the SIPS server without ever passing through the Promod company's server.
After confirmation of the order, the payment request is routed real time in the secure automatic payment system of Sogenactif, where a request for payment authorisation is made to the credit card network. The automatic payment system then produces an electronic certificate.
For payment via Visa and MasterCard, Promod only accepts CES (Commerce Electronique Sécurisé) transactions with the international protocol 3D Secure, recognised by the method Verified by Visa and MasterCard Secure Code. Commerce Electronique Sécurisé is an initiative to guarantee secure payments over the internet. By paying through a secure means, the system automatically checks that the credit card is active on the Commerce Electronique Sécurisé. Then a connection is made with the card issuing bank, requesting authorisation for payment with a personal authentication code. Payment only goes ahead if the issuing bank confirms the authentication code. Otherwise, the transaction is refused.
Top
Article 7: Delivery information
Promod.eu delivers right across the European Union: Belgium, Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, Greece, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Malta, Portugal, Romania, Slovakia, Slovenia, Sweden, The Czech Republic and The Netherlands.
Deliveries are made by carrier from Monday to Friday to the address you have indicated, within a period which depends on the country and the method of delivery chosen (please see the table below).
If you want to send a gift, we will gift-wrap your parcel and insert your personal message at no extra cost. No mention of price will be enclosed with the delivery and the invoice will be sent to your email address.
Except in the case of force majeure, delivery dates are in accordance with stocks available, as indicated below. Promod accepts no responsibility or liability for late delivery for any reason whatsoever. Therefore, no request for compensation of any kind can be claimed by a Promod customer.
Promod reserves the right to select the transporters and to organize the transport. The transport risk passes to the consumer at the moment of delivery.
The web customer undertakes to check the packaging and contents of the parcel and undertakes to write down any problem on the delivery note provided by the transporters.
Rates and times:
Promod delivers your order to your chosen address (your home, workplace or a friend's...). The delivery address need not be the same as the invoicing address, as in the case of a gift, for example.
Deliveries take place during office hours: please ensure that the delivery can be received at the chosen address. The carrier will try to deliver three times before returning the parcel to us.
Destination
Delivery option
Delivery time
Delivery cost
Belgium
Normal
(DHL WELTPAKET)
6 working days
4.50 €
Bulgaria
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Croatia
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Cyprus
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Denmark
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
8.00 €
Estonia
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Finland
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
6.00 €
Greece
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
6.00 €
Hungary
Normal
(DHL WELTPAKET)
4 working days
4.20 €
Express
(DHL EXPRESS)
2 working days
8.40 €
Latvia
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Lithuania
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Luxembourg
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
6 working days
5.40 €
Malta
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Romania
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Slovakia
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Slovenia
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
10.00 €
Sweden
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
6.80 €
The Netherlands
Normal
(DHL EXPRESS)
4 working days
5.00 €
Top
Article 8: Returns and exchanges
The following information on returns and exchanges does not affect your statutory right to cancel according to the Consumer Contracts Regulations.
You have a withdrawal period of 30 days, counting from the day on which you or a third party other than the carrier and indicated by you acquires physical possession of the goods, to return the products you ordered for a refund, if you have changed your mind, if the items received do not match the description or if they are defective.
Web customers may return items, free of charge, in a Promod shop in France (except for Promod outlets and Promod Concessions at the Galeries Lafayette stores of Biarritz, Dax, Lyon Bron and Haussmann), Belgium, Luxembourg and Portugal.
You will be refunded for the returned items within 14 days, counting from the day of receipt by Promod. This period may be extended if the return form is incomplete.
Please note that the original delivery costs (if charged) cannot be reimbursed. Only in case of a complete return, the customer will be reimbursed of the delivery charges. The refund will be made upon reception of all items at the Promod warehouse.
Promod does not propose a direct exchange system. If you want to exchange any of your items, you will have first to return the items that do not suit you and then place a new order to receive the desired items. Please see below for further information on exchanges.
Should you have any queries or claims regarding returns you can send an email, to the following address: service@promod.eu.
Returns conditions:
The online shopper has 30 days, counting from the day on which he/she or a third party other than the carrier and indicated by the customer acquires physical possession of the goods, to return the products. After this date, the items shall be deemed to have been duly accepted by the customer and Promod shall reserve the right to refuse to offer any exchange, credit note or refund.
Goods must be returned in perfect condition and if possible in their original packaging. For items returned via post, the return form must be correctly completed and inserted in the parcel.
Ways of returning goods to Promod:
1)	Via Promod shops:*
You can return the items to a Promod shop, free of charge, within 30 days by bringing along the delivery note and the items to return. The shop will operate the return to the warehouse and you will be reimbursed by bank transfer once your parcel arrived in the warehouse. This could take several days.
*This offer applies to all Promod shops in France (except for Promod outlets and Promod Concessions at the Galeries Lafayette stores of Biarritz, Dax, Lyon Bron and Haussmann), Belgium, Luxembourg and Portugal.
2)	Via the postal system:
The parcel must be returned to the following address:
Promod entrepôt logistique
Service retours
ZA Roubaix Est
51 Rue de Toufflers
59390 Lys Lez Lannoy
France
Return postage costs are to be paid by the customer.
Exchanges:
For every order, the online shopper has 15 days where free delivery is offered on the next order (using the same delivery option as for the first order). If, upon reception of the parcel, the customer decides to exchange an item, a new order can be placed immediately without waiting for the processing of the returns or refund.
Top
Article 9: Privacy policy
Promod is committed to protecting your privacy online. We appreciate that you do not want the personal information you provide to us distributed indiscriminately and here we explain how we collect information, what we do with it and what controls you have.
By using this website, you consent to the collection and use of information in accordance with this privacy policy.
1) Personal data: We can only provide the goods and services ordered by you if you provide us with your personal data. For the purpose of providing these services, we collect personal data about you such as your name, address and email address. We will use the information you provide for the purposes described in this privacy policy to which you agreed to at the time your data was obtained. Your personal data will be used to:
Provide you with the information, goods and services offered through our website and order fulfilment;
administer your account with us;
improve the layout and/or content of the pages of our website and customise them for users;
identify visitors to our website;
carry out research on our users' demographics and tracking of sales data;
send you information we think you may find useful or which you have requested from us, including information about our products and services, provided you have indicated that you wish to receive marketing communications from us.
(2) Monitoring: We may also monitor who accesses our website, for example we may automatically collect access information about you, such as the type of internet browser you use, the website from which you have come to the our website and your IP address (the unique address which identifies your computer on the internet) which is automatically recognised by our web server such information enables us to assess our users, to build a profile.
We also use cookies on various pages on our website. Cookies are small text files that are saved on your computer. This information does not directly identify you and for more information please also read our section entitled "Cookies".
(3) Marketing purposes: Subject to obtaining your consent we may contact you by email with details of products and services, competitions or special offers. If you prefer not to receive any marketing communications from us, you can opt out at any time by sending a written notice with your full name, postal address and email address to service@promod.eu.
(4) Use of cookies: We may also obtain information about your online movements and use of the internet. We do this by placing a ‘cookie’ on your computer’s hard disk. Cookies are used for several reasons, for example to recognise you whenever you visit this website ensuring you do not have to enter all your details and thereby speeding up the process so you do not have to log on each time. It will also enable us to store your personal preferences, build a profile about you and target our marketing and advertising campaigns. We cannot provide a full service to you if you disable the cookie function on your web browser so we advise you to maintain the same. For further information about cookies and how to disable them please go to our help section and read "Cookies".
(5) Disclosure of your personal data: We may disclose your personal data to our agents and service providers (e.g. providers of web hosting or maintenance services) and in any other case where we are required to do so by law or if we believe that such action is necessary to prevent fraud or cyber-crime or to protect the website or the rights, property or personal safety of any person.
(6) Security: We place great importance on the security of all personally identifiable information associated with our users. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information under our control. We will use technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal data, for example:
access to your account is controlled by password and username which are unique to you;
we store your personal data on secure servers;
payment details are encrypted using SSL technology.
You should bear in mind that submission of information over the internet is never entirely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of information you submit via the website whilst it is in transit over the internet and any such submission is at your own risk. All we can do is use all our reasonable efforts to safeguard your data and ensure that we maintain a reliable and safe environment to use your data. It is advisable to close your browser when you have finished your user session to help ensure others do not access your personal information if you use a shared computer or a computer in a public place.
(7) Your rights: Conforming to the data protection act 1998, you have the right to access, modify or challenge your personal data information by writing to service@promod.eu. You have the right to require us to correct any inaccuracies in your data free of charge.
Top
Article 10: Intellectual property
You acknowledge and agree that all copyright, trademarks and all other intellectual property rights in all material or content appearing on this website shall remain at all times vested in us or our licensors. Promod is a registered trademark owned by us.
Every single part of the website, be it visual or audio, including the adjoining technology, is protected by authors’ property rights, brands and patents. It is the sole property of the company Promod. A web user who has a personal website and wishes to publish a direct link to the Promod website must request authorisation from Promod to avoid any implied association with the company of Promod.
Any hypertext link to the Promod site, namely through the use of framing techniques, deep-linking or in-line linking or all other deep link techniques is strictly forbidden. In all cases, any link, even with tacit authorisation, must be withdrawn immediately upon the request of Promod.
Top
Article 11: Liability
As regards all stages of access to the site, of ordering processes, delivery or subsequent services, Promod only accepts partial responsibility. Promod cannot be held liable for any inconvenience or damages caused by the use of the internet network, such as a breakdown in the service, outsider intrusion, the presence of any computer virus or any event of force majeure, as legally defined.
Furthermore, Promod declines all legal responsibility for any failure to comply with contractual obligations in the case of force majeure or unforeseen circumstances, including, but not as an exhaustive list, internal or external company strikes, fire, catastrophe, internal or external breakdowns, and any event in general that could affect the completion of an order.
Top
Article 12: Validity of contract
Should any of the clauses in the contract herewith be made null and void by a change in the law, regulations or a legal ruling, then this shall not affect the validity and adherence to the general conditions of sale as stated herewith.
Top
Article 13: Length of contract
The herewith stated conditions shall remain applicable during the whole of the time that online services are provided by the company Promod.
Top
Article 14: Litigation
These conditions shall be governed by and construed in accordance with French law and you hereby submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the French courts.
Should any litigation arise during the present contractual arrangements, the web customer and Promod shall seek agreement. In the case of litigation, the French courts ruling shall be binding.
Top
Updated on the 13th of June 2014
